Shaik Azeez Ahmed

Technical Specialist

Permanent Address Mysore, KA, 570007

Phone 809-514-9771

E-mail azizahmed648@gmail.com

WWW https://azeez-ahmed.vercel.app/

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/shaik-azeez-

ahmed-7254

Work Status H1B (Nov2019 - AUG2022)

I'm a full-Stack Engineer with 6+ years of experience in building enterprise web applications, with expertise in MVC based micro-services, whitelabelled web-applications and web accessibility.

Believer of **TDD** and **S.O.L.I.D principles**. Religiously follow **agile methodologies**. I enjoy developing simple and clever solutions to complex problems.

Skills

Ruby & Rails, v3.2, 4.0, 5.2, 6.0

Python & Django 8.x

React.js, v16.x

Angular, v2 - v8

Vue.js

Git, Github CI/CD

Web Accessibility WCAG 2.0 (AA & AAA)



Work History

2020-03 - Current

Techincal Specialist/UI Owner (team size: 5)

Infrrd IDP | Infrrd.ai Inc, Bengaluru, Karnataka

- Successfully delivered 3 of biggest client releases which includes both onpremise and cloud environments
- Established advance Git workflow across all teams of the technology stack for code delivery, that simplifies delivery process and ensures quality
- Setup guidelines for code reviews/peer reviews and automated repetitive quality checks on Github
- Interact with different stake holders, product team, UX designers to analyze requirements and create low level design documents for the team

2018-04 - 2020-03

Senior Software Engineer (team size: 8)

Roostify | Infrrd.ai Inc, Bengaluru, Karnataka

- Delivered one of the major projects of Roostify, Inc., weeks before required timelines
- Performed enhancements on various API integrations like Equifax,
 Accountchek, MISMO 3.4, URLA-1003 revision and others.
- Worked on a Hybrid UI (React + Vue + SSR) with backend being Rails 5.1 and Postgres database
- Successfully delivered Front-end to be **98% compatible certification** with WCAG 2.0 web accessibility standards.
- Performed a role of knowledge sharer and mentored juniors with concepts like SSR, Rest APIs, BEM guidelines and Whitelabelled web-apps

2015-06 - 2018-04 **Software Engineer**

Advancion Energy - HMI | Sigmainfo Solutions Pvt. limited, Bengaluru, Karnataka

- Responsible for 5 different on-premise applications, managed new feature enhancements and performance optimization and deployments
- Quickly adapted to working with ModBus TCP/IP protocol for communication between power plant's server and UI client built in Rails & Jquery Mobile
- Successfully refactored and migrated backend stack from Rails 3.2 to 4.0 and then 5.0 beta in stages over a period of 3 months
- Introduced parallel processing with event machine and multi-threading to improve performance for higher capacity power plants
- Worked on enhancing human machine Interface to be configurable and easily scalable to new and bigger power plant with higher capacity and register indicators

Accomplishments

- Awarded Green Horn award for best performer during my training
- Awarded Best employee of the quarter (x2)
- Successfully refactored a Production application single handedly over a period of 3 months outside the regular office hours.
- Built Custom Continuous Integration using Github Actions for quality checks of Pull requests and coding best practices.

Education

2012-09 - 2015-05 Bachelor of Computer Science & Engineering

Vidya Vikas Institute of Engineering And Technology - Mysuru